<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Unofficial</title>
	<atom:link href="https://unofficial.wrfg.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://unofficial.wrfg.org</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 17:12:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Rahul Gandhi takes a dig at Modi over China in US visit</title>
		<link>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/rahul-gandhi-takes-a-dig-at-modi-over-china-in-us-visit/</link>
					<comments>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/rahul-gandhi-takes-a-dig-at-modi-over-china-in-us-visit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[planningadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 17:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://unofficial.wrfg.org/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian opposition leader Rahul Gandhi on Thursday criticized Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s handling of relations with China, saying Beijing was “occupying our territory,” while also taking a dig at the Hindu nationalist leader over the country’s religious polarization. “The fact of the matter is China is occupying our territory. It’s an accepted fact,” Gandhi, who...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indian opposition leader Rahul Gandhi on Thursday criticized Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s handling of relations with China, saying Beijing was “occupying our territory,” while also taking a dig at the Hindu nationalist leader over the country’s religious polarization.</p>
<p>“The fact of the matter is China is occupying our territory. It’s an accepted fact,” Gandhi, who belongs to the opposition Congress party, said in remarks at The National Press Club in a visit to Washington.</p>
<p>“It’s absolutely unacceptable. Prime Minister seems to believe otherwise.”</p>
<p>India’s embassy in Washington did not immediately respond to a request for comment.</p>
<p>Gandhi’s trip comes weeks ahead of Modi’s scheduled US visit later this month.</p>
<p>China and India have been uneasy neighbors for decades following a war on their disputed Himalayan frontier in the early 1960s.</p>
<p>After deadly border clashes in 2020 that killed 20 Indian soldiers and four Chinese troops, China this year ramped up tension by renaming 11 locations in India’s eastern state of Arunachal Pradesh, which China calls southern Tibet and claims as its territory. India has rejected and denied those claims.</p>
<p>In May, Modi said peace on India’s border with China is essential for normal relations between the nuclear-armed neighbours. Since coming to power in 2014, the Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) government of Modi has pumped millions of dollars to boost military and civilian infrastructure along its 3,800-km (2,360-mile) frontier with China.</p>
<p>Separately, Gandhi blamed Modi for India’s religious polarization, saying his Hindu nationalist party was not inclusive.</p>
<p>“They sort of generate a certain amount of hatred in society, they polarize society and they are not inclusive. They don’t embrace everybody, and they divide society,” Gandhi said.</p>
<p>The BJP denies the allegations and says its policies are aimed at the welfare and development of all Indians.</p>
<p>Gandhi also accused the BJP of “capture of institutions” and “capture of the press” in India. Since Modi came to power in 2014, India has slid from 140th in World Press Freedom Index, an annual ranking by non-profit Reporters Without Borders, to 161st this year, its lowest ever.</p>
<p>The BJP denies institutional compromise and says its governance abides by the rule of law.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/rahul-gandhi-takes-a-dig-at-modi-over-china-in-us-visit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Putin gifts historic treasures to church amid Ukraine campaign</title>
		<link>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/putin-gifts-historic-treasures-to-church-amid-ukraine-campaign/</link>
					<comments>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/putin-gifts-historic-treasures-to-church-amid-ukraine-campaign/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[planningadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 17:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://unofficial.wrfg.org/?p=9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For nearly a century, visitors came to Moscow’s Tretyakov Gallery to admire the perfect harmony of Russia’s most famous icon: the “Trinity”, painted by Andrei Rublev in the Middle Ages. The almost 600-year-old artwork depicting three angels is one of the most recognisable Russian masterpieces in the world. Last month, however, President Vladimir Putin handed...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For nearly a century, visitors came to Moscow’s Tretyakov Gallery to admire the perfect harmony of Russia’s most famous icon: the “Trinity”, painted by Andrei Rublev in the Middle Ages.</p>
<p>The almost 600-year-old artwork depicting three angels is one of the most recognisable Russian masterpieces in the world.</p>
<p>Last month, however, President Vladimir Putin handed over the historic icon to the Russian Orthodox Church, the latest sign of the tightening alliance between the Kremlin and religious leaders.</p>
<p>The handover has sparked an outcry from restorers and art historians, who warn the extremely fragile mediaeval icon might not survive outside the Tretyakov Gallery’s walls.</p>
<p>It comes as Russia’s offensive in Ukraine stretches into its second year, with Patriarch Kirill throwing his support behind the assault and saying that dying in Ukraine “washes away all sins”.</p>
<p>Lev Lifshits, one of the country’s leading art historians, warned that the “Trinity” could be destroyed and said he believed the decision to give it to the church was political.</p>
<p>He compared its state to an ailing person.</p>
<p>“If you suddenly take a critically ill person out of an intensive care unit, what do you think would happen?”</p>
<p>Some political observers say Putin’s move is a spiritual decision dictated by the difficult situation on the front line in Ukraine.</p>
<p>“Still no victory,” said political analyst Georgy Bovt. “All that remains is for Putin to ask God for help.”</p>
<p>With Moscow’s military campaign in Ukraine stalling, Russian authorities have been increasingly willing to depict the offensive in religious terms.</p>
<p>The masterpiece was painted for what is now the Trinity Lavra of St. Sergius located in the town of Sergiyev Posad outside Moscow.</p>
<p>After the 1917 Bolshevik revolution, the Soviet authorities transferred the artwork to the Tretyakov Gallery in 1929.</p>
<p>The church said the icon would be first exhibited at the Christ the Saviour Cathedral in Moscow before returning to the historic monastery in Sergiyev Posad. Religious leaders insist they have every means at their disposal to preserve the precious icon.</p>
<p>It is the second transfer of a national treasure to the church in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The Saint Petersburg-based Hermitage Museum said another Russian monastery would receive the silver sarcophagus of Alexander Nevsky, a medieval prince and national hero.</p>
<p>Hermitage director Mikhail Piotrovsky, who has lauded the Ukraine offensive, said it was the right move “at this geopolitical time”.</p>
<p>“Today, the sacred signficance of the monument is more important than its artistic value,” he told reporters.</p>
<p>‘Helped Russian princes’</p>
<p>In a sign the church will not tolerate dissent, Patriarch Kirill has fired and banned from the priesthood a cleric heading the Moscow Patriarchate’s expert council on church art, who said that the safety of the icon was paramount.</p>
<p>Speaking to AFP before his dismissal, Archpriest Leonid Kalinin said the icon’s “rightful place is where it was painted to be”.</p>
<p>Standing in an ornate Moscow church, the cleric welcomed the fact that Putin, a former KGB spy, “turns to shrines in difficult and fateful moments”.</p>
<p>By giving the icon back to the church, Putin wants to “return Russia to its core”, he added.</p>
<p>Putin has sought to depict the offensive in Ukraine as a battle against the decadent West, and used religious symbols to rouse support.</p>
<p>The Kremlin said that during a rare visit to occupied southern Ukraine in April, the Russian president gave troops a copy of a historic icon.</p>
<p>Art historian Lifshits said the “Trinity” had helped Russian rulers in difficult times.</p>
<p>“Contemplating Rublev’s ‘Trinity’ helped Russian princes overcome feuds,” he said.</p>
<p>Popular legend has it that Joseph Stalin, the ruthless dictator of the atheist Soviet Union, also sought divine help in the country’s epic battle against Nazi Germany.</p>
<p>According to one popular myth, in a bid to save Moscow from approaching German troops in 1941, a plane carrying an icon flew over the Russian capital. Two years later Stalin met religious leaders and blessed cooperation between the church and the Soviet government.</p>
<p>‘Unjustified risks’</p>
<p>Rublev’s most famous work has left the Tretyakov Gallery only a handful of times, including during World War II when it was evacuated to safety.</p>
<p>In 2022, the icon travelled back to the Trinity Lavra of St. Sergius for religious celebrations.</p>
<p>Art experts said the piece suffered significant damage when it was temporarily moved.</p>
<p>Lilia Yevseyeva, an art historian at the Museum of Russian Icons in Moscow, said that, if the icon leaves the Tretyakov Gallery for good, “future generations will not see it in its current state”.</p>
<p>Following the public outcry, Putin’s spokesman Dmitry Peskov said the icon would be exhibited at the Christ the Saviour Cathedral, where experts will decide on its future restoration.</p>
<p>Art experts are adamant the piece should not leave the museum.</p>
<p>Even members of the Russian Academy of Sciences broke their silence, saying the icon cannot be moved, “even for a short period of time”.</p>
<p>In an open letter to the culture minister they said only a museum could ensure the preservation of Rublev’s “Trinity”.</p>
<p>“Masterpieces of Russian icon painting and national treasures should not be exposed to unjustified risks,” the letter warned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/putin-gifts-historic-treasures-to-church-amid-ukraine-campaign/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Path is open&#8217; for Ukraine to join NATO: British defence minister</title>
		<link>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/path-is-open-for-ukraine-to-join-nato-british-defence-minister/</link>
					<comments>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/path-is-open-for-ukraine-to-join-nato-british-defence-minister/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[planningadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 17:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://unofficial.wrfg.org/?p=6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Britain supports adding Ukraine to NATO and &#8220;that path is open&#8221; to them, although political realities may slow the process, Defence Minister Ben Wallace said on Friday on the sidelines of the Shangri-La Dialogue security meetings in Singapore. He noted that it is not possible to add members in the middle of a war, and...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Britain supports adding Ukraine to NATO and &#8220;that path is open&#8221; to them, although political realities may slow the process, Defence Minister Ben Wallace said on Friday on the sidelines of the Shangri-La Dialogue security meetings in Singapore.</p>
<p>He noted that it is not possible to add members in the middle of a war, and that the way forward was to continue aiding and arming Ukraine for both short- and long-term security.</p>
<p>&#8220;The best thing we can do to help Ukraine is now to help them defeat Russia,&#8221; Wallace said in an interview. &#8220;After that is to make sure they&#8217;re ready and capable and resilient.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ukraine&#8217;s membership of NATO, the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation, is on the agenda for the group&#8217;s July summit in Vilnius, Lithuania. Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskiy has said Kyiv wanted &#8220;a clear decision&#8221; on its accession at the summit.</p>
<p>Hanna Shelest, director of Ukrainian Prism, a think tank specialising in foreign policy and international security, said in Singapore that NATO membership would be a political decision.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are not expecting to see a strong decision (about Ukraine’s membership) at Vilnius,&#8221; said Shelest, who is based in Ukraine. &#8220;But at a minimum we are hoping for a detailed roadmap.&#8221;</p>
<p>Britain has, alongside other Western allies, provided Ukraine with billions of dollars&#8217; worth of assistance and weapons after Russia&#8217;s invasion, which Moscow calls a &#8220;special operation&#8221;. Most recently, London supplied Storm Shadow cruise missiles, which Wallace said had been 100% successful in striking targets.</p>
<p>Security assurances for Ukraine are also in play, Wallace said, noting that such guarantees could range from mutual defence pacts to providing arms and ammunition. There were few downsides to doing so, he added.</p>
<p>In Asia, he said Britain was committed to supporting the United States and its allies, and to maintaining freedom of navigation on the oceans. He noted that Britain had two warships in the region, and &#8220;that will inevitably grow&#8221;.</p>
<p>He noted that helping Australia develop its next generation of submarines through the AUKUS agreement alongside the United States &#8220;is incredibly important for us all&#8221;.</p>
<p>&#8220;The rise of China, the scale of China&#8217;s military investment, inevitably &#8230; encourages like-minded allies both in the region and indeed the world to work together even more.&#8221;</p>
<p>Chinese Defence Minister Li Shangfu declined an invitation to meet U.S. Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin in Singapore.</p>
<p>Wallace, whose has been mentioned as a possible successor to NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg, said that he &#8220;wouldn&#8217;t say no if he was offered it&#8221;, but that it was up to members to decide.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/path-is-open-for-ukraine-to-join-nato-british-defence-minister/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello world!</title>
		<link>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/hello-world/</link>
					<comments>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[planningadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 17:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://unofficial.wrfg.org/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://unofficial.wrfg.org/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
